boomerang.com 2003-06-18

# boomerang.com | about | policies

Boomerang is committed to a permission-based ethic in providing our e-mail and fax services. Simply put, we don't tolerate spamming. We expect our clients to use mailing lists based on existing business relationships or an opt-in process, and we offer services to help them build and maintain their lists.

Our Acceptable Use Policy in this section specifies the guidelines we follow in working with our clients. Our Privacy Policy describes how we interact with clients and visitors at our web site.  

**Acceptable Use Policy**

Boomerang.com provides services that are intended to enhance business communication between our clients and their customers, prospects and business partners. As such, we expect our clients to use appropriate e-mail and fax mailing lists, and to follow good business practices in keeping with that intent.

The client is solely responsible for the content and the lists used in these transmissions.

_**Our Guidelines**_  
When sending faxes or e-mails to existing customers and prospects, we strongly recommend the use of permission-based, or opt-in lists. This approach is being widely adopted today and serves to enhance the value of the communication. We offer services that allow a company to build an opt-in list for both e-mail and fax services, as well as to supplement and maintain existing lists. 

For every fax or e-mail, we require the sender to provide each recipient with the opportunity to opt-out, or choose not to receive similar communications in the future. Boomerang offers various opt-out services, including a managed reply mechanism with an opt-out acknowledgement for the recipient. Boomerang can also perform the list services needed to ensure that the recipients who opted-out do not receive similar mailings in the future.

Boomerang does not rent or sell mailing lists. We accept business from clients using third-party lists, but the client is solely responsible for these lists and their use must comply with the appropriate guidelines in this section.

We expect all clients to use our services for legitimate business purposes. We will not knowingly accept orders where the content is illegal, pornographic, or indecent. We do not tolerate spam, which is defined as unsolicited commercial e-mail sent to a large number of addresses. Spamming will result in immediate service termination and we will not accept future business from the sender. 

Boomerang currently offers clients the option to store their content and address lists on our system. This is offered for convenience purposes only and is designed solely for use with the e-mail or fax services that Boomerang provides. In keeping with standard practices to safeguard data, we strongly encourage clients to keep current back-up copies of these files on their computer systems.

**Privacy Policy**

Boomerang.com provides e-mail and fax communication services for businesses. Privacy is a fundamental consideration in our interaction with clients and visitors at our web site. This section explains our information gathering and dissemination practices related to our web site.

_**Blast Manager**_ **  
** The Boomerang site includes a link to Blast Manager, a web-based client management tool. This part of the site is restricted to Boomerang's clients and is not available to the general public. In order to access Blast Manager we require a client to correctly enter a user name and password. We use a cookie on the client's system to verify the client's identity and allow access to Blast Manager. This is the only use we make of the cookie.

_**More Information/Newsletter**_ **  
** At our web site, we offer visitors the opportunity to fill out an online form in order to receive more information about the company and its services, or to sign up to receive our newsletter. We collect contact information, such as name and e-mail address, in order to provide these services. Boomerang is the sole owner of the information collected at our site. This data will be not shared with, or sold to third parties.

_**Surveys**_  
Periodically, we may request contact and/or demographic information from site visitors via surveys. These surveys are completely voluntary and the visitor always has the option to decline. Any data collected will be used to evaluate the effectiveness of our web site or specific Boomerang services.

_**Site Data**_  
Boomerang uses IP address data for site administration purposes, troubleshooting, and to assess visitor traffic patterns and the effectiveness of our site navigation. We capture this data using standard traffic analysis software and do not link this data to personal information about our visitors. We may retain this data for up to one year. Other than as described above, we do not currently use cookies at our web site.

_**Security**_  
In providing services to our clients transacting business with end-users, we may take orders from end-users at our web site on behalf of our clients. To fulfill those orders, we may collect personal information about the end-users. We will share this information only with our client. The information will be treated as private and will not be disclosed to any non-affiliated third party or used for improper purposes. Except for the collection of personal information on behalf of our clients, we do not request or collect sensitive personal information at our web site.

In order to set up an account, our clients provide us with credit and billing information. This is currently done over the phone. We treat any such information as private and take appropriate precautions to protect it.

Transmission of information through our web site can be unstable, unreliable and insecure. There is a risk that information may be intercepted illegally.

_**Special Offers**_  
We send all new clients a letter that verifies their user name and password. Occasionally we may send special offers from Boomerang or third parties to our clients. We will always provide a way for them to opt-out of similar mailings in the future.

_**Notice**_  
Boomerang reserves the right to change its privacy policy at any time. Any changes to this policy will be posted on our web site.

Please send any questions about our privacy policy to [privacy@boomerang.com](mailto:privacy@boomerang.com).
